Anh Duy Tran

Ph.D. Student in Software Security

Margarethaplein 9, Leuven, Belgium

© Contact: +32 456 63 02 87

⊠ anh-duy.tran@kuleuven.be

† https://pakkunandy.github.io/



I am a Ph.D. student in the research group **DistriNet** at the Computer Science department of the **Katholieke Universiteit Leuven** (KU Leuven), under the supervision of **Prof. Wouter Joosen** and **Dr.Koen Yskout**. My research focuses include various subjects in Computer and System Security, mostly in Software Security, Computer and Multimedia Forensics, Malware Analysis, Mobile Security, and Privacy.

Education

2022 – Now **imec-Distrinet, KU Leuven**, Belgium **Doctoral Student**, Advisor: *Prof. Wouter Joosen & Dr. Koen Yskout Research*: Applying Automated Threat Modeling Based on Source Code

2017 – 2019 EURECOM and Telecom Paris, (Double Degree), France M.Sc.Eng in Communication System Security, Advisor: Prof. Davide Balzarotti Research: Analyzing Memory Images of Unknown Operating Systems Thesis grade: 20/20

2016 – 2017 **John Von Neumann Institute, VNU-HCM**, Vietnam **M.Sc. in Data Science**

2012 – 2016 University of Science, VNU-HCM, Vietnam
 B.Sc in Software Engineering, Advisor: Prof. Minh-Triet Tran
 Research: Location-based Identity Management and Data Leak Prevention

Thesis grade: 10/10. Valedictorian

Work Experience

2019 – 2022 **University of Science, VNU-HCM**, *Lecturer and Researcher*, HCM, Vietnam. Subject: Software Development and Computer Security

2021 – 2022 **Inspire Lab Technology**, *Part-time Security Engineer*, HCM, Vietnam. Project: Solona-based DApp.

2020 – 2020 **KiteMetric**, *Part-time Security Consultant*, HCM, Vietnam. Project: Security Design for Web Application.

2019 – 2019 **S3 Group, EURECOM**, *Intern Scientist*, Nice, France. Project: Memory Forensics.

 $2014-2014 \quad \textbf{NEC Coprporation}, \textit{ Intern}, \textit{ HCM}, \textit{ Vietnam}.$

Project: Android Application Development.

Selected Publications

- ICIS 2022 Anh-Duy Tran, Quoc-Trung Nguyen, Anh-Minh Nguyen, Minh-Triet Tran. 2022.

 MemInspect2: OS-Independent Memory Forensics for IoT Devices in Cybercrime Investigations. IEEE/ACIS 22nd International Conference on Computer and Information Science (ICIS).
- MMM 2022 Hoang Ngan Vo, Khoa D. Phan, **Anh-Duy Tran**, and Duc-Tien Dang-Nguyen. 2022. Adversarial Attacks on Deepfake Detectors: A Practical Analysis. International Conference on Multimedia Modeling (MMM).
- FDSE 2022 Thanh-Nhan Nguyen, Khanh-Mai Dang, **Anh-Duy Tran**, and Kim-Hung Le, 2022.

 Towards an Attention-Based Threat Detection System for IoT Networks. The annual International Conference on Future Data and Security Engineering (FDSE).
 - SIN 2021 Truong-An Tran-Quoc, Minh-Chi Huynh, **Anh-Duy Tran**. 2021. <u>Towards OS-Independent Memory Images Analyzing: Using Paging Structures in Memory Forensics.</u> International Conference on Security of Information and Networks (SIN 2021).
 - CIS 2021 Anh-Duy Tran, Ngoc-Huy Vo, Quang-Khai Tran, Hai-Dang Nguyen, Minh-Triet Tran. 2021. OS-independent Malware Detection: Applying Machine Learning and Computer Vision in Memory Forensics. International Conference on Computational Intelligence and Security (CIS).
- FDSE 2021 Anh-Duy Tran, Minh-Quan Nguyen, Gia-Hao Phan, and Minh-Triet Tran. 2021.

 Security Issues in Android Application Development and Plug-in for Android Studio to Support Secure Programming. The annual International Conference on Future Data and Security Engineering (FDSE).

Selected Awards

- 2022 Certificate of Outstanding Young Lecturer at HCMUS.
- 2020 Certificate of Merit of Excellent Award in Cyber SEA game 2020, Ministry of Information and Communications.
- 2017 Eiffel Excellent Schlarship for Engineering Student.
- 2016 Second Prize in Vietnam National Competition for Innovation of Students XVIII Euréka.

Skills

- Technical Java, C/C++, Android (at NEC Coprporation), Computer and Software Security, Memory Forensics (at EURECOM), Threat Modeling (at KU Leuven), Hacking skills (for CTF), Teaching skills
- Language Vietnamese (native), and English (fluent)

Services

Secretary 2021: Vietnam Information Security Association, VNISA.

Founder 2019: Computer Security Club, HCMUS, VNU-HCMS

Reviewers 2023: MMM